<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Uses</title>
    <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses.atom" rel="self" />
    <subtitle>Sparvk is an easy to use, yet powerful, portable operating system distribution that can run off a usb stick.</subtitle>
    <updated>2018-12-20T06:50:30+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>sparvk</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses</id>
            <entry>
        <title>Accounting for travel companies</title>
        <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/accounting-for-travel-companies</id>
        <updated>2018-12-20T06:50:30+00:00</updated>
        <published>2018-12-20T06:50:30+00:00</published>
        <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/accounting-for-travel-companies"/>
                <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                        <img alt="" src="/images/4/a/a/a/8/4aaa8a6876b770402dd1249f7b00ac60ed4b6479-startup-593341960720.jpeg" />
                        <p>The accounting in travel companies can get quite complex due to a number of third party vendors involved. For every trip organized you have to arrange for transport, stay and sightseeing, in addition to other misc. expenses like food. The financial transactions often involves back and forth of commissions to not only travel agents but also other parties involved in the journey of a tourist.  </p><p>For a complicated process that requires you to keep track of multiple micro transactions you need an a...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
            <entry>
        <title>An operating system for housing professionals</title>
        <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/an-operating-system-for-housing-professionals%20</id>
        <updated>2018-12-14T04:49:37+00:00</updated>
        <published>2018-12-14T04:49:37+00:00</published>
        <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/an-operating-system-for-housing-professionals%20"/>
                <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                        <img alt="" src="/images/5/e/b/6/2/5eb6231866a251d69fa3559edfb9dca76c928c0e-realestate.jpeg" />
                        <p>Property management is no easy task. You have to deal with a 100 things, all at
once. Not only are you responsible for daily upkeep of your property but you
also have to keep all your residents happy and engaged. A 100% satisfaction rate
is something that is difficult to achieve. No matter how good you are at your
job you will miss things. We understand the challenges involved in housing. </p><p>To help you become more effective in overcoming these challenges we've built
sparvk a portable distributi...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
            <entry>
        <title>Learning tool for students, children and adults</title>
        <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/learning-tool-for-students-children-and-adults</id>
        <updated>2018-12-11T10:56:00+00:00</updated>
        <published>2018-12-11T10:56:00+00:00</published>
        <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/learning-tool-for-students-children-and-adults"/>
                <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                        <img alt="" src="/images/f/7/6/a/2/f76a2ab5b651946e14bc8ccaf715617e1a9ebaca-dawn-1840298960720.jpeg" />
                        <p>A basic computer education is required today to effectively work in any discipline. Whether you're a doctor or a lawyer or an teacher you will need to use computers for your day to day tasks.  The actual use may be as simple as responding to emails or it may be as complex as designing drafts for mechanical components. Proficiency in computers means an increased productivity in your work and improved prospects of getting a job. </p><p>Unfortunately though many of the proprietary systems that  are use...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
            <entry>
        <title>Consistent computing expereince for franchises with sparvk</title>
        <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/consistent-computing-experience-for-franchises-with-sparvk</id>
        <updated>2018-12-05T18:40:54+00:00</updated>
        <published>2018-12-05T18:40:54+00:00</published>
        <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/consistent-computing-experience-for-franchises-with-sparvk"/>
                <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                        <img alt="" src="/images/c/8/6/3/7/c8637a8426f8cf6b2e91e5c295c39991f7aa249c-agreement-2548138960720.jpeg" />
                        <p>One of the great things about computer technology is that once you set it up it can be replicated consistently across any number of machines. It works predictably, reliably and  regularly.  Predictability and regularity are two key requirements for the success of any franchise. </p><p>As a franchiser you want your franchisees to be able to implement key process necessary to provide a level of service that is up to the standards of your brand. New franchises face a different set of challenges that mu...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
            <entry>
        <title>General Uses</title>
        <id>http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/general-uses</id>
        <updated>2018-12-04T04:47:37+00:00</updated>
        <published>2018-12-04T04:47:37+00:00</published>
        <link href="http://sparvk.workrock.in/uses/general-uses"/>
                <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                        <p>A sparvk pod provides a portable desktop operating system experience to its user enabling them to perform everyday computing tasks. Create documents, organize files, read and respond to emails and work on the internet. </p><p>The general utility functions of sparvk makes it an ideal tool for a large number of industries that have to manage documents on a daily basis. Being a low maintenance application, your team can focus on getting things done rather wasting time in getting the (<em>stupid!</em>) compute...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    </feed>
